Detective Jerry Black has made a promise he can't
break, to catch a killer he can't find.
The Pledge is a crime, drama, mystery film directed by Sean Penn.
A police chief, about to retire, pledges to help a
woman find her daughter's killer.
Jerry Black, played by Jack Nicholson.
Doctor, played by Helen Mirren.
Stan Krolak, played by Aaron Eckhart.
Lori, played by Robin Wright.
Eric Pollack, played by Sam Shepard.
Toby Jay Wadenah, played by Benicio del Toro.
The Pledge is a 2001 American neo-noir psychological mystery thriller drama film directed by Sean Penn and starring Jack Nicholson alongside an ensemble supporting cast of
Patricia Clarkson, Aaron Eckhart, Helen Mirren, Robin Wright Penn, Vanessa Redgrave, Sam Shepard, Mickey Rourke, Tom Noonan, Lois Smith and Benicio del Toro.
It competed at the 2001 Cannes Film Festival.
The Pledge is based on Friedrich Dürrenmatt's 1958 novella
The Pledge: Requiem for the Detective Novel.
Dürrenmatt wrote the novella to refine the theme he originally developed in the screenplay for
the 1958 German-language film It Happened in Broad Daylight with Heinz Rühmann.
The film explores themes of promise, murder, drawing, porcupine, pledge.
The tone is intense and emotional and mind_bending.